A Guide to the Francis X. (Frank) Sutton papers FA1141
Rockefeller Archive Center
Francis X. (Frank) Sutton papers
1922-2012
Rockefeller Archive Center
Sutton, Francis X. (Francis Xavier)
Rockefeller Foundation
Social Science Research Council
Ford Foundation
FA1141
56.52 Cubic Feet 114 boxes: 111 legal document boxes, 3 record storage boxes.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Separated Materials
Special format items have been separated from the body of the collection and assigned a unique separation number, as noted. Requests to access open special formats should reference the unique separation number.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Collection donated by the Sutton family on September 12, 2013.
Arrangement
The Francis X. Sutton papers are arranged into six series:
1. Aga Khan University, 1972-2010
2. Ford Foundation, 1936-2012
2.1: Ford Foundation History Project, 1953-2010
3. Rockefeller Foundation, 1975-1997
3.1: Bellagio, 1975-1997
4. Social Science Research Council (SSRC), 1922-2009
5. American Foundation for Intellectual Cooperation with Europe (AFICE), 1983-1995
6. Personal Files, 1948-2010
6.1: Correspondence 1960-2010
Biographical / Historical
Francis X. Sutton was born on July 7, 1917 in Oneida, Pennsylvania. In 1938, he graduated from Temple University with a Bachelor of Science in Mathematics. Following his graduation, Dr. Sutton pursued graduate studies in mathematics at Princeton University, where he taught math and earned a Masters degree in 1940. He received a second Masters in Sociology from Harvard University in 1941. While studying in Cambridge, Dr. Sutton taught sociology at Suffolk University. From 1941 through 1945 he served as an aerial navigator and captain in the United States Army Air Force. Dr. Sutton returned to Harvard following the war and earned a PhD in Sociology in 1950. While pursuing his PhD, he was selected as a Junior Fellow of the Society of Fellows of Harvard University. From 1949 through 1954, Dr. Sutton lectured on Social Relations and served as an Assistant Professor in Sociology and General Education at Harvard. He also taught summer courses at Columbia University and the Salzburg Seminar in American Studies.
In July 1954, Dr. Sutton left academia for a position as Executive Associate in the Ford Foundation's Behavioral Sciences Program. He served in this capacity for three years until October 1957 when he became the Program Associate for the Overseas Development program's Near East and Africa division. In July 1963, Dr. Sutton transferred to the East and Central Africa office in Nairobi to serve as the Overseas Development Representative for the region. In February 1967, following the creation of the International Division the previous year, Dr. Sutton became the Assistant to the Vice President and by October 1968 was promoted to Deputy Vice President. Dr. Sutton served as Deputy Vice President throughout the 1970s and early 1980s. In 1977, he was also named Officer in Charge of the European and International Affairs program which formed part of the International Division. Dr. Sutton officially retired from his posts at the Ford Foundation in June 1983 but stayed on as a consultant for several years to compile a history of the Foundation's international work. Dr. Sutton served as Acting Director of the Social Science Research Council (SSRC) for one year, commencing on October 1, 1985. From 1985 through 1992 Dr. Sutton served as both a member and chairman of the SSRC board and a consultant to several organizations and foundations including the Aga Khan and Aga Khan University, the Ford Foundation, World Bank, the Rockefeller Foundation, and USAID.
Scope and Contents
The Francis X. (Frank) Sutton papers primarily consist of material related to Sutton's time at the Ford Foundation, spanning his tenure as Assistant to the Vice President, Deputy Vice President, and his work writing the history of the Ford Foundation as a consultant. This collection documents Sutton's involvement beyond the Ford Foundation as well; it contains a substantial amount of information on the Aga Khan University in Pakistan, the Rockefeller Foundation and Bellagio Conference, and the Social Science Research Council (SSRC). Additionally, there is a small amount of material on the American Foundation for Intellectual Cooperation with Europe (AFICE) which documents its foundation and eventually, its termination. Personal files can be found at the end of the collection (Series 6) which consist of family correspondence, awards, publications, datebooks, and notebooks – most of which document Sutton's cross-organization involvement, travels, and projects.
Ford Foundation; Rockefeller Foundation; Ford Foundation history; Aga Khan University; Social science -- Research -- Developing countries; International education
- Aga Khan University, 1972-2010; 1; 13.78 Cubic Feet 29 letter document boxes and 1 oversize box
  - Institute of Islamic Civilisations (IIC) Task Force, London Meeting, 1998-1999; 1998 December 1-3 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - University of Khorog, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bishkek Conference Paper, "Scientific Knowledge as a Basis for Education for High Moutain Peoples", 1996 (Box 1, Folder 3-3A)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Folder 3A is closed to research - contains personal information.
  - Tajikistan - Khorog, 1993-1995 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Kyrgyzstan Reports, 1995 August (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Khorog Correspondence, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Scope and Contents
    Contains photographs.
  - Khorog Extras, 1997 October (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Khorog Karachi Meeting, 1997 February (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Khorog Mission, 1996-1997 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Khorog Dushanbe Meeting, 1997 May 13-24 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Kyrgyzstan Mission Papers, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Council on Foreign Relations (CFR) - Islamic Movements, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Council on Foreign Relations (CFR) - Muslim Politics, 1995-1997 (Box 2, Folder 13-14)
  - Council on Foreign Relations (CFR) - Pluralism in the Modern World, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Kyrgyzstan - Osh State University, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Eurasia Foundation, 1993 September (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Chancellor's Commission, 1992-1996 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Khorog Geneva Meeting, 1997-1998 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Trip Expense Accounts, 1996 June-July (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Europe Trip - Organization Commission Meetings, 1997 September-November (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Wagner - National Center on Adult Literacy, 1991-1994 (Box 3, Folder 22-22A)
    Folder 22A is restricted from research - contains personal information.
  - Wagner - National Center on Adult Literacy, 1994-1996 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Wagner - International Literacy Institute, 1995-1996 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Wagner - International Literacy Insititute, Hamburg Trip, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Wagner - International Advisory Committee (IAC), Literary Research Center, Jamaica, 1992-1993 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Wagner - Comparative and International Education Society (CIES) Meeting, Boston, 1994-1995 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - The Aga Khan University - Tenth Anniversary, undated (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Plaque, 2013:053:001 (Box 115)
      Separated Materials
      Special format items have been separated from the above listed file and assigned a unique separation number, as noted. Requests to access open special formats should reference the unique separation number.
  - Human Development, 1993-1994 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Education and Human Development, 1983-1990 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Education, 1992-1993 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Trust for Culture - AKU Architecture, 1992-1993 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Health Sciences, 1992-1994 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - International University Grants Design, 1992-1993 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Chancellor's Commission - Governance and Finance, 1992-1993 (Box 4, Folder 35-36)
  - Chancellor's Commission - London Meeting, 1993 September (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Chancellor's Commission - Planning, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Islam and Aga Khan University, 1991-1994 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Islamic Universities, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - The Ismaili Centre, London, undated (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Sudan Islamic Campaign, undated (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Founding of Aga Khan University Address, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Karachi - Planning, 1992-1993 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Karachi Meeting, 1993 February 17-18 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Karachi Meeting - Agendas and Papers, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Karachi Meeting, 1994 March 29-31 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Karachi Paper, 1996-1997 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Washington Meeting, 1992 October 24-25 (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Endicott House, 1993 March-May (Box 6, Folder 50-52)
  - Meeting - Drafts/Extras, 1993 May (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - United Nations University (UNU), 1992-1993 (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - Future of Aga Khan University Meeting, New York City, 1994 February 17-19 (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - Chancellor's Commission - Draft Report on the Future of Aga Khan University, 1994 September (Box 7, Folder 56-57)
  - Chancellor's Commission - Final Report on the Future of Aga Khan University, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 58)
  - The Medical Centre Committee - Final Report, 1993 July (Box 7, Folder 59)
  - The Medical Centre Committee - Rector's Summaries, 1993-1994 (Box 7, Folder 60)
  - Aga Khan University Project, 1982-1983 (Box 7, Folder 61-62)
  - Expenses, 1992-1995 (Box 8, Folder 63)
  - Institute of Islamic Civilizations (IIC) Survey Report, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 64)
  - Institute of Islamic Civilizations (IIC) Central Asia Visa Correspondence, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 65)
  - Institute of Islamic Civilizations (IIC), 1997 (Box 8, Folder 66)
  - Institute of Islamic Civilizations (IIC) Survey of Research and Studies on Islam and Islamic Civilizations, 1997 February (Box 8, Folder 67)
  - Institute of Islamic Civilizations (IIC) London, 1998 January 25-27 (Box 8, Folder 68)
  - Chancellor's Commission - London Meeting, 1993 September 13-15 (Box 8, Folder 69)
  - Chancellor's Commission Meeting, 1995 March 21 (Box 8, Folder 70)
    - Papers for New York Meeting, Georgina Coch, 2013:053:008
  - Medical College Convocation Addresses, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 71)
  - Health Science Faculty Inauguration, 1985 November 11 (Box 8, Folder 72)
  - Medical Centre, Karachi - Annual Report, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 73)
  - The Aga Khan Health Services International Newsletter, 1994-1997 (Box 8, Folder 74)
  - Aga Khan Foundation - International Strategy Report, 1991-1999 (Box 9, Folder 75)
  - Development Network Bulletins, 1992-1995 (Box 9, Folder 76)
  - California State University - Commencement, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 77)
  - The Future of AKU: Evolution of a Vision, Report of the Chancellor's Commission, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 78)
  - AKU Report, 2008 (Box 9, Folder 79)
  - Correspondence, 1992-1995 (Box 9, Folder 80-83)
  - Board of Trustees Meeting, 1992 October (Box 10, Folder 84)
  - Board of Trustees Meeting, 1994 May 29-30 (Box 10, Folder 85)
  - Board of Trustees Meeting, 1994 July (Box 10, Folder 86)
  - Science - Correspondence, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 87)
  - Science - Memorandum, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 88)
  - Science - Papers and Articles, 1977-1983 (Box 10, Folder 89-90)
  - Task Force - Higher Education and Society, 1997-1998 (Box 10, Folder 91)
  - France, 2001 (Box 11, Folder 92)
  - Memo - Steering Committee, London Meeting, 1993 July 4 (Box 11, Folder 93)
  - Pluralism and Its Cultural Expressions (Box 11, Folder 94)
  - Biographies of AKU Staff, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 95)
  - Aga Khan University History - Correspondence, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 96)
  - Women's Studies, undated (Box 11, Folder 97)
  - Trip File, Karachi - Nairobi, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 98)
  - News Articles and Speeches, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 99)
  - Bell Economic Development, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 100)
  - Single Donor Universities - "Weaning" Report, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 101-101A)
    Folder 101A is restricted from research - contains personal material.
  - Possible Courses for Development of AKU, 1983 October-November (Box 11, Folder 102, Box 12, Folder 104-105)
  - Development Network, undated (Box 12, Folder 106)
    Contains three booklets, one titled "The Aga Khan Development Network in East Africa."
  - Development Network - St. Thomas Medical School, 2002 (Box 12, Folder 107)
  - Newsletters and Clippings, 1996-2008 (Box 12, Folder 108)
  - Aga Khan University Progress Report, 2008 (Box 12, Folder 109)
  - The Ismaili - Aging in America: Changes and Challenges, 2010 (Box 12, Folder 110)
  - Dawood College of Engineering and Technology, Karachi, 1990-1991 (Box 12, Folder 111)
  - Prospectus for a Central Asian International University: Report of the Commission on the Establishment of an International Institution of Higher Education at Khorog, Tajikistan, 1998 (Box 12, Folder 112)
  - Report of the Task Force on Improvement of Higher Education in Pakistan, 2002 January (Box 12, Folder 113)
  - Pakistan, 1992-1993 (Box 12, Folder 114)
  - Central Asia and Afghanistan, 1992-1993 (Box 12, Folder 115)
  - "Towards an Education Strategy" Book 1 - Architecture Education in the Muslim World, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 116)
  - "Annexures-Quantitative Data" Book 2 - Architecture Education in the Muslim World, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 117)
  - Islam - Conference on Islam in the Political Process, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 118)
  - Aga Khan Program for Islamic Architecture (AKPIA), 1985-1993 (Box 13, Folder 119)
  - Aga Khan Program for Islamic Architecture (AKPIA) Harvard and MIT, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 120-121)
  - Aga Khan Program for Islamic Architecture (AKPIA) Meeting Booklet, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 122)
  - Aga Khan Program for Islamic Architecture (AKPIA) Review, 1992-1993 (Box 14, Folder 123)
  - Council on Foreign Relations (CFR), 1994 (Box 14, Folder 124)
  - Aga Khan University Project - India Trip Report (Box 14, Folder 125)
  - Aga Khan University Project - Bangladesh Trip Report, 1983 March 18-22 (Box 14, Folder 126)
  - Health Management, 1993-2007 (Box 14, Folder 127)
  - Ghulam Ishaq Khan (GIK) Institute of Engineering Sciences and Technology, 1993 (Box 14, Folder 128)
  - Mehtab S. Karim, 1993 (Box 14, Folder 129)
  - Context and References, 1992-1999 (Box 14, Folder 130)
  - College of Arts and Sciences (CAS) - Proposal for Planning, 1999 November (Box 14, Folder 131)
  - Central Asia - Education and Development, 2000-2002 (Box 14, Folder 132)
  - Arts and Sciences Proposed Schedule, 2002-2003 (Box 14, Folder 133)
  - Program for the International Conference: "Mountain Research - Challenges and Directions for the 21st Century," Bishek, 1996 October 14-18 (Box 14, Folder 134)
  - Plan for the Institute of Islamic Civilisations (IIC) - Final Report of the Task Force, 2000 December (Box 15, Folder 135)
  - "Higher Education: A Pathway to Development," Keynote Address - Karachi, 1996 November 20 (Box 15, Folder 136)
  - Jacqueline Sutton Correspondence - Karachi, 1996-1997 (Box 15, Folder 137)
  - Higher Education at Khorog, Karachi Meeting, 1998 June 28-30 (Box 15, Folder 138)
  - Convocation, 2003 (Box 15, Folder 139-141)
  - Distance Learning, 1998 (Box 15, Folder 142)
  - Asian University for Women Planning Conference, Wellesley College, 2002 (Box 15, Folder 143)
  - Paris Trip, 2001 June 27- August 11 (Box 15, Folder 144)
  - FAS - Boston Harvard Club Meeting, 2002 September-October (Box 15, Folder 145)
  - Liberal Learning for Practical Purposes - BRAC University Study, David W. Fraser, 1996 (Box 15, Folder 146)
  - College of Arts and Sciences (CAS) - Planning Meeting, Toronto, 2001 July (Box 15, Folder 147)
  - College of Arts and Sciences (CAS) - Academic Design Paper, 2002 (Box 16, Folder 148)
  - College of Arts and Sciences (CAS) - Academic Design Paper Background, 2000 November-December (Box 16, Folder 149)
  - College of Arts and Sciences (CAS) - "Basic Education Design of a College or Faculty of Arts and Sciences", 2001 (Box 16, Folder 150)
  - College of Arts and Sciences (CAS) - "Basic Education Design of a College or Faculty of Arts and Sciences" - Background Materials, 1992-2001 (Box 16, Folder 151-152)
  - College of Arts and Sciences (CAS) - Central Asia, 1995-2001 (Box 16, Folder 153)
  - College of Arts and Sciences (CAS) - Correspondence, 2001-2002 (Box 16, Folder 154)
  - College of Arts and Sciences (CAS) - Liberal Arts, 1997-2000 (Box 16, Folder 155-156)
  - College of Arts and Sciences (CAS) - Liberal Arts, Bowdoin College, 2000 (Box 17, Folder 157)
  - College of Arts and Sciences (CAS) - London Meeting, 2002 (Box 17, Folder 158)
  - College of Arts and Sciences (CAS) - Science Articles, 1998-2002 (Box 17, Folder 159)
  - Communications, 1982 (Box 17, Folder 160)
  - Higher Education Articles, 1994 (Box 17, Folder 161)
  - Khorog University, 1997-1998 (Box 17, Folder 162-164)
  - Khorog University - Budget and Staffing, 1997-1998 (Box 18, Folder 165)
  - Khorog University - Chantilly Commission, 1997-1998 (Box 18, Folder 166)
  - Khorog University Commission, 1997 (Box 18, Folder 167)
  - Khorog University - Geneva Meeting, 1997 (Box 18, Folder 168)
  - Khorog University - Geneva Paper, 1998 (Box 18, Folder 169)
  - Khorog University - Legal Basis, undated (Box 18, Folder 170)
  - Khorog University - Organizational Committee, 1997-1998 (Box 18, Folder 171)
  - Khorog University - Organizational Paper, 1997 (Box 18, Folder 172)
  - Khorog University - Potential Sites, 1997-1998 (Box 18, Folder 173)
  - Khorog University - Reading Materials, 1997-1998 (Box 18, Folder 174)
  - Khorog Meeting, Washington DC, 1998 (Box 18, Folder 175)
  - Dushanbe Meeting, 1998 March (Box 19, Folder 176)
  - Karachi Meeting, 1998 June (Box 19, Folder 177)
  - Law, 1983 (Box 19, Folder 178)
  - Law - Mayer/Salacuse Papers, 1982-1983 (Box 19, Folder 179)
  - Law - Pakistan, 2001-2002 (Box 19, Folder 180)
  - Management, Asian Institute of, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 181)
  - Management - Harvard Study, 1982-1983 (Box 19, Folder 182)
  - Medical Center Committee Report (Draft), 1983 (Box 19, Folder 183)
  - Sudan, 1982 (Box 19, Folder 184)
  - Ana T. Gutierez, 1982-1983 (Box 19, Folder 185)
  - AKU Project Budget, 1983 (Box 19, Folder 186)
  - Development Network, undated (Box 20, Folder 187)
  - Trust for Culture - New York Meeting, 2002 (Box 20, Folder 188)
  - Multi-Campus University Systems, 1984 (Box 20, Folder 189)
  - Board Meeting, Geneva - Program Strategy for the Aga Khan Foundation, 1983 October 7 (Box 20, Folder 190)
  - Department of Education and Health, 1984-1994 (Box 20, Folder 191)
  - The Imamat's Economic Development Activities, 1984 June 19 (Box 20, Folder 192)
  - Harvard-Drager Conference on Population Interactions between Poor and Rich Countries, 1983 (Box 20, Folder 193)
  - Taiati Monograph, 2003 (Box 20, Folder 194)
  - Khorog University, 1997 (Box 20, Folder 195)
  - Rural Development, 1982-1983 (Box 20, Folder 196-197)
  - Medicine and Public Health, 1982-1984 (Box 21, Folder 198-199)
  - Brochures and Newsletters, 1982-1983 (Box 21, Folder 200-201)
  - AKU Report - Earlier Draft and Background Materials, 1989-1994 (Box 21, Folder 202)
  - Karachi, 1993 November (Box 21, Folder 203)
  - Revisions to Commission Report/Exchanges with Georgia, 1994 (Box 22, Folder 204)
  - Future of Aga Khan University Draft Report, 1994 (Box 22, Folder 205)
  - Aga Khan Medical Center Executive Summary, 1993 May 23 (Box 22, Folder 206)
  - Maternal Mortality, undated (Box 22, Folder 207)
  - Health Policy and Management, 1992 (Box 22, Folder 208)
  - Culture and Solipsism, 1987-1991 (Box 22, Folder 209)
  - Education, 1982-1983 (Box 22, Folder 210-211)
  - Islam, 1973-1984 (Box 23, Folder 212)
  - Islam - Articles, Reviews, Papers, 1979-1984 (Box 23, Folder 213-214)
  - Islam - David King, Islamic Science, 1983 (Box 23, Folder 215)
  - Islam - Humanities, 1972-1992 (Box 23, Folder 216)
  - Islam - Humanities and Civilizations, 1993-1994 (Box 23, Folder 217)
  - Islam in the Modern World Report, 1984 (Box 23, Folder 218)
  - Modernity and Islam, 1995-1996 (Box 23, Folder 219)
  - Islamic Universities, 1984-1993 (Box 24, Folder 220)
  - Islamic World (Box 24, Folder 221)
  - Institute of Islamic Civilizations (IIC), 1996 (Box 24, Folder 222)
  - Institute of Islamic Civilizations (IIC) - Europe, 1996 (Box 24, Folder 223)
  - Institute of Islamic Civilizations (IIC) - Malaysia and Singapore, 1995-1996 (Box 24, Folder 224)
  - Institute of Islamic Civilizations (IIC) - Iran and Turkey, 1996 (Box 24, Folder 225)
  - Institute of Islamic Civilizations (IIC) - Uzbekistan, 1996 (Box 24, Folder 226)
  - Institute of Islamic Civilizations (IIC) - Survey, 1993-1996 (Box 24, Folder 227-228)
  - Institute of Islamic Civilizations (IIC) - Survey Concepts and Plans, 1996 (Box 25, Folder 229)
  - Institute of Islamic Civilizations (IIC) - Survey Correspondence, 1996 (Box 25, Folder 230)
  - Institute of Islamic Civilizations (IIC) - Survey Texts (Material from Azim), 1996 (Box 25, Folder 231)
    - Azim's Paper on IIC, 2013:053:009
  - World Bank Meeting, 1992-1993 (Box 25, Folder 232)
  - Karachi, 1996 November (Box 25, Folder 233)
  - India Trip, 1983 (Box 25, Folder 234)
  - Kenya Trip, 1982 (Box 25, Folder 235)
  - Pakistan Trip, 1982 October (Box 25, Folder 236-237)
  - Chancellor's Commission - New York Meeting, 1994 (Box 26, Folder 238)
  - Aga Khan Foundation - Correspondence and Reports, 1983-1984 (Box 26, Folder 239-240)
  - Institute of Ismali Studies Visit, 1982 October (Box 26, Folder 241)
  - AKU Project - Asia Trip, 1981-1983 (Box 26, Folder 242)
  - AKU Project - Bangladesh Trip, 1983 (Box 26, Folder 243)
  - AKU Project - Contract File, 1983 (Box 26, Folder 244)
  - AKU Project - Trip Reports, 1983-1984 (Box 26, Folder 245)
  - AKU Committee - Meetings and Correspondence, 1984 (Box 27, Folder 246-249)
  - International Literacy Institute - Board Meeting Minutes, 1996 (Box 27, Folder 250)
  - AKDN: Aga Khan Development Network, undated (Box 27, Folder 251)
    - AKDN: Aga Khan Development Network, 2013:053:002
  - Pakistan Clippings, 1995-1996 (Box 27, Folder 252)
  - Miscellaneous Notes and Articles, 1991-1994 (Box 27, Folder 253)
  - Publications, 1981-2010 (Box 28, Folder 254-257)
  - Aga Khan University Notebooks, 1995-1996 (Box 29)
- Ford Foundation, 1936-2012; 2; 24.02 Cubic Feet 51 legal document boxes
  - Staff Biographies, 1988 (Box 30, Folder 258-259)
  - Staff Biographies - Correspondence, 1997-2003 (Box 30, Folder 260-261)
  - Staff Obituaries, 1995-2012 (Box 30, Folder 262-264, Box 31, Folder 265)
  - Personnel Directory, 1968 March (Box 31, Folder 266)
  - Personnel and Reorganization, 1981-1984 (Box 31, Folder 267-269)
    Folder 269 is restricted from research - contains personnel information.
  - Salaries, 1975-1981 (Box 31, Folder 270)
    Closed to research - contains personnel information.
  - Budgets and Expenditures, 1966-1981 (Box 31, Folder 271)
  - Financial Management (Box 32, Folder 272)
  - Historical Financial Report, 1936-1954 (Box 32, Folder 273)
  - Governments and Development, 1967-1976 (Box 32, Folder 274)
  - Education and Development, undated (Box 32, Folder 275)
  - International Institute of Tropical Agriculture in Africa, 1963 (Box 32, Folder 276)
  - "Nation Building in the Heyday of the Classical Development Ideology: The Ford Foundation Experience in the 1950s and Later", 2004-2005 (Box 32, Folder 277)